{
    "id": "2bf74934e77d4b3f992dc62d5268e739",
    "title": "Modal Auxiliary Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "They knelt in front of the child who ............................ one day rule their country.",
            "description": "The main verb is in the past tense, so we need an auxiliary referring to the past time in the dependent clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "shall"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b2fc2a72fea2433388e88987b783007e"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many people ...................... get into a telephone booth?",
            "description": "We use 'can' to talk about theoretical possibility. ",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "can",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "692bfa98fe254ad8a60f9f8a4af754ee"
        },
        {
            "question": "I .............................. not do this if I did not have to.",
            "description": "If the verb in the if-clause is in the simple past tense, we use 'would + infinitive' in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "should"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8fe6f71d34f041378ee1ec3a4c7682f1"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you stopped talking, I ......................... get some work done.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "might",
                "could",
                "Either 'might' or 'could'"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "c0076a95dd8b4f189ff4d1c5d5b29b9d"
        },
        {
            "question": "................................. a visa for Malaysia?",
            "description": "The auxiliary need is followed by an infinitive without to. ",
            "answers": [
                "Need I to get",
                "Need I get",
                "Do I need get"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "28be447b798046cb8b4a2523f47fc7c8"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ........................... better start saying thank-you.",
            "description": "The correct expression is 'had better'.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "should"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6e836253c7a74d3ca6294a303d8594ed"
        },
        {
            "question": "Let's go for a walk, ............................ we?",
            "description": "After 'let's' we use 'shall we' in question tags.",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "shall",
                "will"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4631b5b6b7104f3c84b738a9864aac1b"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ............................... work on Sundays.",
            "description": "Need can be used as an auxiliary verb and as a regular verb. When need is an auxiliary, it is followed by an infinitive without to. When need is used as a regular verb, it is followed by an infinitive with to and questions and negatives are made with do. ",
            "answers": [
                "needn't",
                "don't need to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0eb0d72036934975a269dc2dd4edbd10"
        },
        {
            "question": "She really ........................... to mend her ways.",
            "description": "Ought is followed by an infinitive with to. ",
            "answers": [
                "should",
                "ought",
                "must"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "373deb4c0219426e85f739e4e2d4e247"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ............................. speak six languages.",
            "description": "We use can to show ability may indicates possibility.",
            "answers": [
                "may",
                "can",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b76e10365a1c479eb506306dff42a35d"
        },
        {
            "question": "Life ............................... be more interesting when I was a child.",
            "description": "Would cannot be used to talk about habitual states in the past. Only used to is possible with that meaning. ",
            "answers": [
                "used to",
                "would",
                "use to"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5cca77db0ae34335ba6c12dc38a68b0b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Granny ....................... always bring us nice gifts.",
            "description": "Both 'would' and 'used to' can be used to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "would",
                "used to",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6645c81110a8407393cf1d23f229a7cd"
        }
    ]
}